# TYLER POORE DATA SCIENTIST

■ tylerjpoore@gmail.com

**\** 307-609-1035

New York, NY

in tyleripoore-1825

Pooret

I am an entrepreneur-turned data scientist, ML/AI enthusiast. Currently, I am a Springboard Data Science Fellow with project experience in data analysis and visualization, NLP, machine learning, and deep learning. I have over 7 years of experience in market research, adoption strategy, and product development for early-stage biotech companies. Outside of work I am an avid skier, fitness nerd, and I love 80's synthpop.

#### **Skills**

#### **DATA SCIENCE**

Python

SOL

Data Analysis

Data Visualization

Machine Learning

NLP

**Bayesian Statistics** 

MySQL

Hadoop

Deep Learning

Tensorflow

Inferential Statistics

#### **ENTREPRENEURSHIP**

User Engagement

Prototyping

**Public Speaking** 

Shareholder Engagement

Lean Startup

Startup Operations

**Medical Devices** 

Market Research & Strategy

Fundraising

## PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT (CHEMISTRY)

Organic Chemistry

Polymer Chemistry

Natural Products

**Product Characterization** 

Nanotechnology

Product Manager

**Product Roadmap** 

## **Employment**

Data Science Fellow

Springboard

New York Jan. 2021 to Current, Jan. 2021 to Current

- 550+ hours of hands-on curriculum, with 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and completion of 2 indepth capstone projects
- · Mastering skills in Python, SQL, data analysis, data visualization, hypothesis testing, and machine learning.
- Trained in time-series analysis, deep learning, model deployment, NLP, image processing, and Hadoop.

Capstone Project 1: Predicting Stock Movement using Executive's Tweets

IrOs. LLC.

New York, NY Mar. 2015 to Nov. 2019

Co-Founder

- Co-Founded biotech company that 3D printed biomimetic hydrogel drug-releasing scaffolds as antibiofilm dissolvable sleeves for implantable medical devices
- Led end-user engagement to understand the pain point of current practices and develop potential solutions with engineering team
- Acted as product manager, in which I worked with end-users, engineers, and management to develop a
  product within cost and production
  constraints that met the needs specified through iterative usertesting
- Performed market research and developed strategies for IP, reimbursement, scaling and distribution, and regulatory approval
- · Developed a pricing model that incentivized preventative measure through reducing annual hospital costs
- Created a 3-D printed model that allowed for rapid prototyping and end-user assessment

ExSponge, Inc.

New York, NY Nov. 2013 to Ian. 2015

TO

- Development of novel, covalently-bound antimicrobial fibers that are safe, non-leaching, and don't lead to antimicrobial resistance.
- Developed a method for synthesizing biomimetic polymers using microwave-assisted ring-opening polymerization with various antimicrobials.
- Co-authored two provisional patents with Columbia University's tech transfer office.
- Created and presented pitch decks to raise startup capital, bring on board members and company hires, and present results and progress to shareholders.

## **Projects**

#### Concussion Prediction with RNN

Current

Stock Movement Prediction using Twitter

I performed a binary classification that predicted company stock movement using company executive's tweet data. 5 years of stock and twitter data were collected for 6 companies and their executives. Stock movement was predicted using SVM and Logistic Regression Classifiers with features engineered from the company executive's tweets. The best model was an SVM classification using Richard Branson's posts that predicted Virgin Galactic stock movement with 81% accuracy, and an f1 score of 62% for the stock movement (82% for no stock movement).

An Efficient Approach to the Securinega Alkaloids Empowered by Cooperative N-Heterocyclic Carbene/Lewis Acid Catalysis

Developed a novel approach that uses N-heterocyclic carbenes (NHCs) and Lewis acids to forge the entire domain of securinega alkaloids through an ynal-derived homoenolates intermediate.

## **Education**

Columbia University
MS Organic Chemistry 2013

2010 to 2013

Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute BS/MS Chemistry 2010 2005 to 2010

## **Activities**

PetFinder.my - Pawpularity Contest · kaggle competition group Predicting the popularity of shelter pet photos that to improve animal welfare. Current